[Music]
welcome to launched I'm Charlie Chapman
and this is the annual Christmas special
with the one and only Jordan
[Music]
[Applause]
Morgan Jordan welcome back to this very
uh continually running show that we have
here I do one podcast a year and I Make
It
Count I'm getting close to being in the
same category uh I think this is I think
our Christmas special from last year was
like three episodes ago uh
approximately uh so I guess I guess
we'll just address that right off the
bat here uh We're Not Dead Yet launched
uh it's still alive obviously we're
always going to do the Christmas special
till the day we die Jordan has signed a
contract for that marked in blood uh
marked in blood uh I actually do I have
nothing to announce but as as they say
In The Biz things are in motion uh we're
still we're still in the same mode we
were before don't expect regular
episodes right now but uh I am trying to
get some pieces in place so I can maybe
get launched back into into some sort of
regular Cadence but we're not there yet
TBD T exactly uh so yeah so for anybody
who's somehow listening to this and
doesn't already know what's going on I
guess if this show gets going again uh
in Earnest maybe they'll be going
through the back catalog and be confused
when they listen to this this is the
annual Christmas special with with
Jordan Morgan uh we started this I think
the first year that I started the show
which at this point is like 5 years ago
which I guess this episode was then four
years ago and this is this is our
opportunity unlike a normal episode
that's about everybody else this is kind
of the episode where we get to sit and
talk about our feelings as uh Indie app
developers in in the App Store world I
guess yeah I mean this is year number
four we've gradu I mean this Christmas
special is graduating high school this
year that's crazy graduating well so our
first year was our freshman year yeah
freshman year what year did you go to
high school I don't know what it's like
down in Souther Missouri didn't you
graduate high school in fourth grade for
I guess third grade kindergarten yeah
2021 that's the one that I have on my
website was the first one yeah I guess
to to sort of kick off the conversation
then there's been some pretty major
changes uh in your life definitely in
the last year so technically I think you
knew that this was happening but you
hadn't announced it publicly that you
went from a real job as an iOS Developer
to joining the dark side that I had
joined last year of uh developer
advocacy uh where we sort of fake being
iOS developers do you want to tell tell
the people uh one what did you do and
then how's how's that been going I mean
if there's any career ambition I've
always had it's to have a fake job um so
I'm very hashtag blessed for it yeah no
uh let's see so the long story short is
uh I've been at my previous job buffer I
think nine I was coming up on nine or 10
years I can't even remember at this
point but you know you stayed at a
company a while um kind of start
wondering what you want to do next uh
and I kind of was getting to that point
I think a lot of software Engineers go
through it where you just kind of get a
little jaded I want to say not so much
with the the company but just just the
The Daily Grind of fixing bugs trying to
meet deadlines get projects out you know
being the engineer uh capital E and so
kind of was was starting to feel the
brunt of doing that for so long and when
I kind of was uh you know chatting
through this with my wife and you know I
think even in the in the group chat it's
always met having this podcast cuz like
everything that I'm saying I've already
said to you but you know it's like you
know what's next what do I want to do
and and I think I actually talk to to
David about the position that you have
before you had applied for it like you
know months ago and at the time I was
like David the growth Advocate at
Revenue cat yeah Revenue cat and I was
like yeah you know I'm I'm GNA I'm I
think I'm all right at buffer right now
and you know changes so big and scary
when you've been at a company that long
right you kind of you're so comfortable
you know how things go um for Better or
For Worse what each day is going to look
like and so switching that up was like a
huge like leap of faith for me
especially since you know my wife Janson
stays home I have three kids you know so
any career change I kind of want to feel
good about um but one point my wife made
was like well you kind of want to feel
good about like being happy about what
you do every day and you don't really
seem very happy doing what you do every
day uh and again I still talk to tons of
people from buffer it's that's not a
slight of buffer they you know they
treated me very well for a long time it
was just more too late you just burn
that bridge down uh might well just
slander for the rest of the show exactly
uh a buffer burnfest the rest of the way
no but you know I it was really clear
that like I needed to change of pace and
I remember I I I reached out to three
companies it was when I decided like
mentally like yes I'm going to look for
something else kind of see how it feels
it was uh I I dm' Josh from emerge uh
tools um I talked to browser company got
pretty far in the process with them um
but then realized I was just going to be
jumping straight back into like some
pretty hardcore engineering and then I
dm' Jake and Jake was hilarious to chat
with the CEO of or founder this that
whole you know everything I'm talking
this is where me being a professional
podcaster who does this regularly all
the time I bring my expertise to the
fold exactly so Jake is the CEO at Super
wall where I work I I've known Jake for
a long time and when I dm'd him he was
just like heck yeah man let's do it uh
you know it's very nonchalant like let's
let's let's go before I even knew what I
was doing you know um and the thing that
sold me was he said like I want you like
if you come here I just want you to make
Swift jective C which is my personal
blog website I just want you to do that
for us and I was like that sounds
phenomenal um you know I'm almost at a
year in I think and January 15th but
like the thought of writing for lack of
better work content for a company and
being paid for it as opposed to like
really you know in the trenches with
engineering just sounded like exactly
kind of what I needed um at the time
coming up for air and I I got to say
yeah coming up for air and I got to say
like it it does feel fantastic because
I'm sure you know um and we can talk
about the intricacies of like how we
both do things uh in in the same role
but it's it's such a different field
than engineering because because the way
that I explain it is like you have to
have been an engineer to kind of do the
things that me and you do like it would
be hard to jump straight into a
developer relations role in the way that
we have them in our companies I'm sure
there's a huge span of what those roles
look like but for me it's like if I
don't know how to program or read docs
or write docs for that matter then like
I can't really do this so there's this
little niche of people that I think are
emerging in the industry right now that
have been Engineers for a long time but
also have those written communication
skills and like that's a good mix for a
developer for Advocate um and yeah and
that's kind of what the thought process
behind getting to that point but I I got
to say I I love the job I love the role
it's not that it doesn't come without
its own set of pressures and stress but
they are definitely different like not
feeling the weight of a
deadline like my I if if I could
tangibly measure my stress this past
year it just went like it nose dive down
you know it's like oh man I hope I can
get this article done instead of being
like I just shipped a bug that you know
screwed up 50,000 users you know worklow
you know the the the stresses are
different and it's and it's what I need
because like as we just kind of it's
it's really surreal that we have these
talks every year I mean because we're
just getting older and older man I mean
there's more gray hair uh every every
gray hair and it's just like my kids you
know they're getting older and I I care
more about spending time with them and
you know being a better dad all those
things and it really just got to the
Tipping Point for me and I think a lot
of people hit this in this career where
it's like
man I'm stressed out a lot and I and I
kind of bring it home I'm a little bit
more quiet I'm just trying to decompress
and get back into dad mode and to have a
job where like you don't feel that
anymore um makes a huge difference and I
got to say I love the small feel too um
I mean at Super wall there's I think
eight of us um and for anybody listening
uh me and Charlie were joking about this
yes we are sworn enemies working at
rival huge tech companies um and and our
sole mission is to destroy the other one
so um as I mentioned Charlie my only
reason for doing this is to bring back
Intel of course and uh try and try and
obliterate Revenue cat once this posts
obviously so you know super wall is a
great partner of Revenue cat uh we're
happy people to
use so there's all these all these
mangled tangled webs wee weave I guess I
think that's uh I I may have mentioned
this last year because I'm assuming we
talked about this last year I only
listened to like half of the episode cuz
I've been busy but
uh the one of the weird things about
this job for me and I I assume it's
somewhat similar for you is like I used
to maintain a really strict like curtain
between my jobby job and all the Indie
and online stuff that I did and all of
that just got completely
obliterated uh doing this Dev Advocate
thing because part of the reason I was
hired and it sounds like part of the
reason you were hired is to bring that
person into the company like that's
literally the point uh so you're
supposed to talk about you and be you
publicly as an employee of that company
and that that has been kind of
interesting and it's not it's something
I think I would have been uncomfortable
with before but I I'm used to it now and
it doesn't really make me uncomfortable
at all you make a great point because
that's one of the things that I like
about the role
is like before if I found like an
interesting new API because we're just
super weird nerds and pour over xcode
documentation for fun and entertainment
like normal people speak for
yourself you know uh like when I find
those things like my urge is like maybe
to like just tweet it out be like oh has
anyone check this out but like I think
in like traditional roles or other jobs
or like tech companies that are also
online you're like you know I don't
really want to tweet this right now
because like I'm on my quote unquote
work hours you know there's all these
Optics involved whereas now that's like
it's so fun because that's like my job
the more that I be myself and share like
even side projects the thing that I'm
working on the things that I write about
it's truly like a symbiotic relationship
where it just helps me um because I
enjoy it and it also helps super wall
because like you said you kind of
personify the company in a way where you
can associate yourself freely with the
people that you're a developer advocate
for and that's why like I feel like this
job was really like kind of made for me
at this point in my life because I just
want to write I want to share stuff uh I
love sharing stuff I always have you
know I've been on this podcast for years
now saying that and I feel like we both
found a job that like pays us to do that
um and it's that old adage you know that
corny phrase you hear like all the job
fairs when you're in high school college
it's like find something you love and
you never work a day in your life you're
like yeah okay whatever you know um but
you know you kind of come back around
it's like oh [ __ ] shoot like there is
there is some truth to that you know um
the more you enjoy your job who knew the
better hey little moosey I see him
popping up there he's got I was about to
say I don't uh we're attempting to do
this on video uh so assuming this is on
video you will apparently see my dog
just pop his head in the frame as he
just did to get my attention uh I feel
like Paul Hudson right now um you might
be able to hear him just going to town
on a bone over there too he's been very
quiet all day till moment I hit record
yeah let him cook uh something that I I
think is interesting
about what we've both done in the last
you know year and a half with this sort
of job switch
is I feel like we we sort of personified
a thing that the CTO at this company
that I first interned with uh they were
a like
chemical like reselling company for
scientists it was not like a tech job at
all right um and he didn't they know
what to do with interns I was there for
like kind of a weird reason uh and every
once in a while he would like take me
into his office and like give me advice
but it was like really generic and I
remember him telling me he's like you
should go into chemical engineering he's
like because if you can do if you can do
chemical engineering and computer
science you're worth your weight in gold
like you're the most valuable person
ever and I was like I have no interest
in chemical engineering so that was not
something that I pursued but that for
whatever reason that stuck with me and
I've heard versions of that my whole
career which is if you are really into
something else outside of whatever it is
your main job is most people listening
to this probably software development or
whatever and you are also into something
else then those two combined make for a
very unique set of skills that there's
probably not a lot of people who also
do% and both of us are weird in that
we're nerdy developer types but we also
like the sort of content creation side
of things we like talking to people and
I think we both do this developer
Advocate job extremely differently which
I think we should talk about here in a
second but like in both cases we found a
role based on all this extra side work
that we've been doing for forever where
we could sort of Leverage that to
combine the very real skill of like
decades or decade plus of software
engineering experience with the thing
we're passionate about and then found a
job that sort of combined those two yeah
but you have to have both exactly it's
not like we're just doing the thing that
we're passionate about it's like we're
bringing along like I I do think there's
a lot of people that want to go into
like this Dev Advocate thing right away
out of out of school and and there's
probably places you can do that uh with
but I think for both of what we're doing
we're the only ones at are company and
like you really have to have that full
round edness of all that engineering
experience and be passionate about the
the actual uh content side of the house
if that makes sense yeah I mean because
at the end of the day you're you're
writing stuff for people like you and me
um who were Developers for a long time
so like if you don't know how to speak
to them relate to them or know what
their needs are uh it's hard to do this
job um but you are right about like kind
of how those things converge together
and how it just you know there's that
little Spurt of uh of sunshine that
starts to peek through when you I get in
that role that feels really right and uh
I remember like the first week that I
started at Super W it was something with
payment links and apple where where they
air quote allowed external payment links
do you remember that where like there
was that crazy scary modal that you had
to show like it was like they did but
they really yeah yeah uh and I remember
Jake was like Hey can you write
something about that and it was weird
and I remember texting Jan and I was
like I can't believe I'm like getting
paid to do this right now cuz you know
that
yeah and I was so used to like you know
grinding it out on code or whatever it
was um and I'm like I'm writing a blog
post and being paid like a tech salary
for it like it feels like cheating you
know it's crazy that is how I feel every
time I open after effects at work oh my
gosh and to to people in the like at
Revenue cat you know they're like it's
like I'm going above and beyond and to
me I'm like anytime I've ever done
something something like that regular
work it was like me stealing time away
like I'd feel guilty and I'm rushing
through it and yeah it's it's kind of
incredible being able to do a thing that
you actively love doing and we're not
even talking about being an indie
developer is also part of this job uh
it's kind of important that we still
understand that World um that's actually
something I was going to ask you about
too is like cuz again this whole
episode's very introspective me and you
are both conservative people not
politically meaning I just mean like a
political podcast let's pivot let's go
yeah yeah we're hard pivot welcome to
2024 but like we overthink most things
to both of us we did a career change
with this right something I've actively
thought about a lot both before and
since uh and I still think about
frequently is like this like you just
said a second ago we have to understand
the development World in order to do our
jobs well but we're no longer living
day-to-day in the engineering World
we're not you know submitting PRS and
doing code reviews and all that stuff
does that worry you ever like are you
concerned about like not burning out but
like losing touch with the people that
we're supposed to be talking to because
that's not the world that we live in uh
it doesn't for me at all and the reason
why is I think I have an even better
balance of that now because one and this
is maybe a result of working at such a
small empy employee based small company
is that I still do engineering stuff uh
quite a bit like you know we're making a
client app right now and I've done
almost all the work on that um and there
we added RSS I haven't tweeted about it
because I still need to fix some tweaks
but it is actually live and prod and
like so I got to get my hands dirty with
react and nextjs which I'd never done
ever to kind of get the RSS feed working
so there's these little pockets of
engineering that I can go and like seek
out to do so even at my day job when you
take the Indie side out of it which
we'll get to I still code quite often um
and I and I love that and and that's the
thing about developer advocacy is I
think it just it's so different I think
everywhere that's the sense that I'm
getting because I'm sure there's roles
that at like apple a huge you know
established company where you would
never do that but I kind of like my my
role almost changes every week like some
weeks I'm only writing documentation
some weeks I'm making YouTube videos
some weeks I'll dip in on some
engineering work some weeks I'll just
Hammer the support inbox and spend a lot
of my time there um so it always kind of
varies and then if there's a big release
coming out you know I want to get a blog
post for it things of that nature uh but
no in my case I don't because I can
still I have the luxury of still trying
to code if I if I want to code um in the
role yeah I that last point is something
I found immediately too like whenever I
switched over I did the thing I try to
always do which is be way too extra and
read literally everything there is to
read about what is being a developer
Advocate and almost immediately I
learned it's a meaningless word and
everybody does something different and
who knows 1,000% I didn't read any of
that I was like I'm just going to wing
it I I remember when you first told me
that you were switching over to this
role I was excited because my first
thought was like I in the whatever year
it had been that I'd been doing it I was
like I've never found somebody who
actually does is exactly what I do I've
met other developer Advocates but it's
like the moment I start talking to them
I realize H they're doing pretty much a
totally different thing yeah but then
you started and then it's like H you're
essentially doing it your own totally
different thing as well like there's of
course overlap for sure um but it still
feels like we're we're
operating our own just totally different
thing it is yeah and that was one thing
I was told is Jake said like there's no
manager for this like you're just gonna
make it up as you go you know and I feel
like that's really a great way to
describe developer advocacy because you
know trying to help out developers with
your product or company it just looks so
different all the time I mean sometimes
it's maybe I need a new video uh over
this certain feature and that's that's
why I like kind of going all over the
place because like some of the videos I
do on our YouTube channel they're a
result of me like helping out on support
and I'm like all right people are having
a a lot of issues with this particular
part if I can just do like a
three-minute video explaining it then I
can just there you go here's a video
problem solved and I love that part of
it um and speaking of videos I I always
joke like with Jake uh and then when I
all uh your CTO at on wwec I I joked
about your video production skills too I
was like when I started at Super wall I
I told Jake right away I'm like listen
I'm not going to be able to match
Charlie's whizbang cool intros and and
top-notch quality
so let's just make sure we we're good
there and understand that you know I
can't do his After Effects mumbo jumbo
see that's my that was my worry in the
opposite direction I'm like ah Jordan's
going to come in here and show everybody
what like a good writer actually looks
like and we just need I'm not going to
be able to compete yeah we we need to
just merge our powers uh because you
know writing's always been my strong
suit and I enjoy I love writing uh and
I'm starting to enjoy video more but
like even before this I was not even not
even joking this was serious right
before we recorded I'm like hey I got
this new DJI mic there's knobs on it I
don't know what any of this means so
like my audio sucks you know so like
that that whole world is still really
new to me and I and I've picked up a
little bit uh over time to try and make
things a little bit better uh but like
just that's such a different skill set
that you really have to to kind of
develop and and I think did you do
multimedia stuff in college as well or
is this just like something you always
enjoyed and just kind of taught yourself
along the way I've yeah I've always done
it like as a hobby side project I not
Consulting but like I would do projects
for churches and local ad agencies and
stuff so it's been a strength of years
for so yeah yeah yeah this is not
something I just decided to pick up and
figure out it's like a birthday present
I got in college uh was after effects
and that was one of the most that's
probably still the greatest not birthday
Christmas gift I've ever gotten in my
life uh it was just like unbelievable to
me that I had access to this thing uh
that I'd been watching tutorials about
even though I didn't have access to it
my uh version of After Effects is
choosing a default animation and cap cut
to show the super wall that's about like
as far as my skills go with that stuff
uh but it is fun I I really do enjoy it
um and YouTube gives you such a dopamine
hit like do you I feel so accomplished
anytime I upload a video you know I'm
like ah there it is you know you I think
that's the developer Advocate version of
like shipping a new feature or something
it's like when I get a blog post out or
a new feature um and that's actually
another good thing I actually wanted to
bring up with you it's like one thing
that was tough for me in the beginning
is feeling like you didn't have this
like tangible
deliverable stuff that you did
throughout the week like we'll have the
stand up on Monday and we'll all go
through what we did and I'm used to
being like yes this thing is on track or
these bugs were fix where I research
that whereas now your output is is a lot
different it's like I made the demo
project for this blog post that's going
out you know it's really in- depth it's
good um you know it's a foundation I can
use going forward but that takes that
can take like your whole week you know
you could be making a demo project all
week and if you have things like daily
check-ins or something like that you
know at first you're like a little
self-conscious like all right well I was
still working on you know a demo project
but it's like a mind
uh set shift that you have to have that
takes a little bit um and there was
never any external pressure or anything
but it in in your own like internalized
pressure it's very weird that was the
biggest thing I think for me that it
took to get getting used to in a Dev a
developer Advocate role is like just how
your output is not Cod anymore and like
to turn that part of your brain off
takes it took me months to kind of get
that through my head yeah I definitely
felt the same because what what I've
learned quickly was like one of the
things I was better at is these big
hence the name of the show I guess
launches like yeah very quickly I was
pretty uh like deeply in bed with the
product team and the big launches that
we do creating content for them and that
was like really easy for me uh but I'm
not very fast at writing and the sort of
more like generic not generic but like
Evergreen content that's not related to
a specific product feature or something
just the weekly blog post kind of thing
yeah exactly and we would have these uh
you know these strings of time where a
bunch of teams were all hitting at the
same time and so a bunch of products
were launching and it's like my world
would be crazy and I'm like pumping out
all these videos and i' feel super
productive and then it would be this LOL
period while everybody's building
actually building things and all of a
sudden I would just feel like I'm
preparing a lot I'm building a bunch of
products uh projects internally I'm
sending bug reports like hey this
doesn't seem to work right whatever uh
I'm meeting with customers uh to learn
about problems that they're having
whatever but it was like whoa where's
all this like output and suddenly I
would feel super like uh oh they're
going to find out they're finally going
to realize I don't know what I'm doing
cast out of the bag um developer
Advocate his face
exactly and then uh and then you know
there'd be a new slew of features that
would come and eventually I learned to
like be more okay with those lull
periods uh because what I would try and
do is focus on getting quick
wins and but then I wouldn't be as
prepared for when the slurry of new
stuff came uh because I was just out of
the loop on everything and so being in
the loop uh whether that's internally
within my company's like bigger um and
so there's lots of teams there's a lot
of things just happening and it doesn't
get pushed to you you have to sort of
seek it all out I feel that too even in
at our size yeah and being in the loop
online which sounds weird I remember
whenever I first was in a meeting and
one of our other people actually I think
it was David their growth Advocate said
something about like it's weird but like
part of my job is just dming people on
Twitter and I would be like uhuh yeah I
say that too and now I'm like it
legitimately like it's crazy how often
you know we'll be like hey does anybody
know anybody at XYZ company in Hong Kong
and it's like oh yeah I know like three
people over there and it's like that
didn't come for free that took a lot of
me being aggressively like meeting
people talking to people maintaining
relationships which to be honest this
goes back to the I can't believe I'm
getting paid for this that's what I like
to do anyway um but it is like a part of
the job and sometimes it can be really
time consuming but then when it pays off
you you were like okay that was worth it
even though that was 10 minutes of my
time 30 times of the last 2 years or
whatever uh that was all worth it now
once you actually you know get the
payoff but the payoff is like so down
the line that it's hard it's very
different than normal software
development and and you do quite a few
conferences too that's that's something
I haven't done in the role yet is like
you know we go to deep dish Swift uh the
best world renowned conference that
there is in the planet uh you know and
that's it I I've been there and and that
was funny because that my first time
like working a booth at a conference
like actually being I don't know for
lack of a better term yeah you know and
you know people kind of shy they Mosey
up there a little bit and you're like
hey you know like you want to talk about
super wall or you know things of that
nature and that was another I can't
believe I'm getting paid for this moment
too you know like going to a conference
that I would pay to just go to on my own
um anyways and I don't know I think what
we found out is if you're just uh social
lunatics who love programming then maybe
developer advocacy is a good career
choice for you yeah yeah it's a weird I
I do think it's a weird
uh it's a weird job and it's it's so
specialized uh cuz to do it I mean Maybe
I'm Wrong maybe our two like we said our
two jobs are unique no i' say that all
the time I don't think there's a huge
overlap of people that could do it yeah
and like I don't think I could
transition to being a developer Advocate
at Google
unless it was about well I couldn't at
all cuz it's like iOS but like it's it's
like yeah like I have this skill set of
like making videos and writing blogs and
stuff now but like what really makes I
think us to make sense for these roles
is like we're Indie devs who know and
implemented subscriptions into our app
already and that's a thing that we're
interested and passionate about and
creating content about anyway MH and it
really is it's less about like I don't
know I guess if like if if you heard
about this and you were like man that
sounds like a career opportunity for me
it's like what would my advice be to do
it it's like well first spend a decade
doing the engineering work and then you
know what I mean it's like but I do
think at like a bigger company where
they have big teams there is a lot more
people that are specialized at yeah like
apple has someone that just rides docs
and just does you know videos just does
this where does me and you we're just
kind of doing all of those things um bad
versions of all the things yeah we're
what is it the the term you know master
of none but kind of okay at all of it so
I mean that's kind of how you have to be
with developer advocacy yeah I I I do
say a lot like I feel like I get to do a
cheating version of like almost every
role at the company like that's a good
way to put it like I get I'm sure you
get this too I get a lot of DMS from
people for customer support things it's
like oh I get to like put on my customer
support hat and like oh I'm helping you
out with this thing but the moment it
gets too hard for me or I'm busy and I
don't want to do it right now or
whatever I can be like yeah sorry man
like I'll let me send you over to our
actual customer support team and then
they deal with it uh same with like
customer calls I get to go on customer
calls all the time or potential customer
calls but then it's like but I'm not
actually in sales so I don't have to
like actually do the hard part of that
job 100% And like engineering it's like
I can like submit a PR here and there
but it's like but nobody's expecting me
to anytime I do it it's like oh thank
you for doing some extra work for us and
beond
yeah so it's like every I do is like a
cheap uh cheating version of all these
different hats which we've talked about
I think on the show is part of what we
liked about Indie development is we like
wearing all the hats we like learning
about marketing and learning about
customer support and learning about all
these things and in the Indie context
are fully responsible for it but it's at
least smaller in scale yeah and you get
to learn so much that you actually want
to learn like you're going to learn at a
job no matter whether you want to or not
no matter the vocation or role that you
have um it's just part of working
somewhere but like one thing that really
appealed to me was super wall is like
you know like Jake especially he's he's
built an app and like kind of
bootstrapped one on his own that did you
know like several million in Revenue um
and along the way he needed something
like super wall which is uh if I
remember correctly kind of how the
company started at the time um but like
those are the things that I wanted to
learn because like I had had apps for
years but none of them like made enough
money to where like they could just be a
job that I had and you know being able
to share with them when I started to and
to say like hey you know like I kind of
hope this is the last job I have to be
honest like I want to learn from you and
and do great here and I want to learn
how to grow and make enough money
someday to be able to just make software
on my own um and he was like he yeah man
let's do that um and that's that's the
really fun thing is like we we see a lot
of what works on the App Store and what
people do um and you can pick up those
things and apply it to your own work and
uh try and you know get in growth mode a
little bit more and you know when we
talk about the Indie stuff I think
that's the big biggest them for me this
last year too is I kind of thought a lot
less Indie and more of just like how do
I make this make money you know like how
do I make things grow and become
profitable enough for me to take them to
that next level and you see it all the
time at Revenue cat you see it all the
time at Super wall all these companies
that are just you know doing insane
amounts of money on apps that you would
never ever guess um and some that you
would some are very obvious but it's
it's so interesting to look at that data
and you know kind of learn from it and
see the trends and and what's working
and what doesn't because it changes all
the time so let's actually let's move on
to that uh you know we've talked enough
about uh being developer Advocates now
let's get to what the the people really
want to hear about which is the ndfs uh
so last year we talked about you had
recently I think launched Elite Hoops so
it's been a little over a year since
that's that's been out how's that going
for you first as my job as host here
remind the people what Elite Hoops is
and then uh and then tell us how it's
been going yeah it's uh so what it
started at is a way to quickly share
like plays Concepts defense whatever uh
for your basketball team so I used uh
replay kit to do screen recording with
audio on like your iPhone iPad and it
works on Mac too um and the idea was
like there's this whiteboard just like
you would have in real life but if you
could record it and send it to your team
you could explain things a lot quicker
so uh of course I love basketball you
know my son's played year round since
you know was four you know it's it's
like a huge part of our family we love
watching basketball every night what's
your what's your uh what's your email
address again uh oh this is a good
inside joke that numers bring everybody
in on so I've had the same email since
no joke fourth grade bball the number
four not four life the word four life
and then like a few numbers at the end
that were like my favorite basketball
numbers and like I've always had it and
I joke with this about this all the time
like I filled out mortgage applications
with that like big boy jobs like Social
Security anytime there's like a it's the
worst something where it's like hey
what's everybody email and you get you
know Charlie M
Chapman gmail.com or you get person's
name at me or me or whatever and then
and then you always see bball bball for
Life uh numbers coming from Jordan I
think I had like I was doing a credit
check or something you know when when we
bought our last car like all right all
right Mr Morgan like just need your
social all right now what's a good email
for you I'm like ball for
life have you never like have you
created a more more professional
sounding one I did I have like uh theore
Morgan forf now so like I've been using
that more but like I just have like 20
whatever years of like using that email
address um that's amazing you know the
shame wears off as the years go on I
don't even care anymore I'm just like
yep here it
is oh man so part of your personal brand
yeah wa so we love basketball so it you
know the app was natural for me because
I love you know being in that area um
but it's kind of grown since then so
like and it kind of goes back to what I
was foreshadowing before about kind of
learning from the companies that are
doing you know the App Store well and my
thing with Elite Hoops is I wasn't going
to think of it so much as an indie app
like where I really wanted to get like
you know the Press coverage or you know
the App Store feature which to be clear
I would I would absolutely love those
things I still still try for them but I
had a huge emphasis on those as growth
levers before and I kind of got to the
point where I like I'm just going to try
and make my own luck with this thing so
uh in a blog post I just put up last
night actually about like a big feature
I just shipped it's this whole practice
planner Suite to where like you can
create drills you can make practice
plans and then you can run them
interactively on your phone kind of like
how Instagram stories goes through your
stories or you could just print it out
yeah and that was the first time where I
really like I talked to a bunch of
coaches um I know several personally
from just you know uh being involved
with basketball so long you know my
neighbor is a college coach um um I look
through a lot of my data I look through
a lot of the feedback to kind of arrive
at that decision to do that whereas
before I just kind of made what sound
interesting and fun to me and so I kind
of learned that lesson over the course
of so many years and I don't know why it
took so long to learn the lesson of
build what people actually need and that
sounds so incredibly obvious but like
when you sit at your computer and you've
been at work all day or you've been a
dad all day and you have this little
nugget of time going through feedback is
isn't really fun like you just want to
build something that gets that
creativity that expression out or that
new API that you want to use you know
your mind doesn't go there I think
there's a lot of there's a lot of advice
online that is people saying build what
you love the best thing the best apps
are the ones made by people solve own
problem that has the passion in it yeah
solve your own problem and like I don't
think that's wrong there's a lot of
great examples of apps because I do
think you're generally especially if you
don't have
a strong sort of product sense which
never had to be clear yeah then building
something for yourself is way easier you
are a product expert in that field you
know yourself really well you don't have
to figure that out so in a lot of ways
it's a lot easier but it's not strategic
in terms of targeting a an audience of
any sort of size or potential customer
base of any sort of size um and so yeah
some of the best apps I I have seen in
terms of performance are people whenever
I talk to them they kind of sheepishly
are like yeah I don't actually even
really use it myself like they sort of
accidentally ended up into it or they
made it for themselves when they were in
college but they're way out of that
they're not in that stage of life
anymore but they're still building
excellent software for that group of
people um and I think that's just as
valid sometimes it's even beneficial um
to be a little bit outside of it cuz
you're not building something particular
to you you're a lot more open
to actually targeting it towards the
market yeah no that's that's completely
true and it's just like you know at the
end of the day people are going to pay
for something that really solves their
problem and I know everyone's heard that
a million times it's on every product
podcast it's on every product blog post
like what I don't know why it just never
went through my head you know and and
again I think we're in a very specific
niche of people that love making
software on their own to where like your
creative energy is kind of Trashed by
the time you have time to actually work
on this stuff you know so it got to the
point where I was like I'm just going to
be ruthless about this like if I can't
make this make money I'm not going to
work on it um and now it's when you look
at it as more of a product and less than
an India app that's been the shift that
I personally needed to kind of grow it
and to make it better um and you know I
bootstrap all of it and it's an
interesting uh time to be talking about
it actually cuz I think I in the group
chat the other day I was like hey you
know that was my best day on Elite Hoops
like
6145 in one day um something like that
but since then it's it's kept that pace
like within a few hundred every day um
and it's been so exciting to see like
the momentum actually really start to
pick up and one shift that I made is
like before if I had any kind of side
project income you know it was just that
like you know use it for vacation you
know just some nice to have stuff you
know it's not that much money but it's
it's nice to have that little extra
income um that's you don't just dump it
into an account for fear of the tax man
for years like I did Charlie has $6
trillion do saved up for anyone
listening and uh I have been like the
I'm too scared to spend any of it but 6
trillion It's all under a mattress uh in
the house but what I've done with a lot
of the money that I've making with Elite
Hoops is I'm pouring it right back into
the product so for example I started
with $30 of Apple search ads when it
first launched and my my little logic
was like if I just get one conversion
like baby steps if I can just get one
person to convert for
$45 then I mean yeah you got to take
taxes all that stuff away but like at
least I come out on top so like I
started there and I've just slowly
scaled up as the year's gone on to where
now I spend uh $160 in advertising every
single day just on autopilot and then
I've seen the the revenue go up to like
5 or 600 and so like at the turn of the
Year I'll look at it again and be like
all right so should I up this to 2 to
300 and then if the revenue scales with
it then I'll just I'll just keep going
until it doesn't work but that only
works if your your lifetime value per
customer that you're acquiring through
those is lower than uh or is higher than
whatever the cost of that ad was right
uh yeah I guess I don't really look at
charts very much I look at I look at uh
this is this is where I my product
knowledge goes down the window I look at
Mr and like I love looking at what I
make each day um so that's the way I've
looked at it you know as long as I get
the conversion a day you know then then
I'll the thing the thing is what you
don't know is if if you turn those off
would your Revenue go
down more or less than the amount you're
spending for sure and that's where you
really have to experiment so I did that
and I just kept a simple Excel
spreadsheet and I I think I divided up
into like four things this was like 4
months ago uh and the the slots were
just like organic you know no apple
search ads no meta ads nothing just
Apple search ads just meta ads just an
Instagram boosted post and I think
that's all I tried and organic like you
you run it for a week or something like
what is that they two weeks for each one
so it took like a couple months okay
excuse me but they were over different
periods of time yeah I didn't run them
at the same time so I just did like all
organic no advertising for like two
weeks then I just did like cuz I don't
really have like great tracking in there
like I don't even use the Facebook SDK
still so it's just like I can just kind
of see what that's where the Apple
search ads one is better yes very very
much so it's super helpful to kind of
look at those things because there you
can actually figure out
what right cuz ultimately I think that's
what you have to do if you want to I
mean if your goal is just to grow your
audience or your user base then and you
don't care if you're making money or
losing money then yeah you can just like
pour money into all these things but if
you want it to be profitable then you
kind of need to be able to figure out
what is the actual lifetime value I'm
getting out of the customers coming from
that ad right yeah and do you can you
only really know LTV after like you've
been out on the app store for a year and
kind of seeing your turn rate and kind
of how people are sticking around cuz I
only recently hit that like I don't know
what was it late October I think is when
that one year mark hit for me I mean I'm
certainly not an expert at this but I
think the way most people look at this
is they'll look at the LTV over a period
of like 30 days or 90
days um and so really what that tells
you is like if you have an annual plan
you're like you said it was like $50 a
year or whatever then you get $50
immediately it doesn't matter if they
turn after that or not um if you have
monthly I think that's where people
maybe look at the 90-day more than 30
days but the the reason for that is uh
unless you're like you have a bunch of
capital because you're like VC funded or
something uh you what you really need to
know is am I getting the money back that
I put into the machine within this set
period of time otherwise you can't keep
putting money in the machine cuz you run
out yeah uh totally before you even get
that back and so I think that's what
most people are looking at is 30day or
90 days um and that's why like which is
if you're if you're using Apple search
ads um I I can only speak for Revenue
cat I promise this isn't a shill but
like we have a like LTV chart that you
can look at and just see what those are
oh no i' I've used it uh alah Hoops
launched with Revenue cat you know I
launched that before I started at Super
wall and yeah no I used that chart cuz
we talked about this a long time ago I
forgot when but like you were showing me
how to use the chart to to kind of
at this exact thing you know to figure
out LTV um and for a while Apple search
ads were just killer for me uh but then
I had a competitor come out and I guess
just kind of outbid me on all of those
and then it didn't work so I've had this
journey of like apple search ads were
like the money magic machine and then
then they weren't and then I kind of
figured out meta ads a little bit more
and like kind of researched those pretty
heavily tried a bunch of different
creatives um really thought about like
if I would was just kind of swiping
through Instagram or Facebook like what
what would speak to me what would make
me actually want to install this app and
so you know I really kind of honed in on
messaging and and little tiny things uh
and I think I heard this on the sub Club
podcast when someone was on I forget
their name uh specializing in meta ads
and they were talking about like the
audience filters like you can say you
want to Target you know this this age
range and he basically said something to
the effect of like the lower age range
Maybe on by default but like those ads
are really cheap to serve up to people
on Facebook's or meta network but they
don't convert particularly well and I
was like man I should look at that
because most basketball coaches and
there are a ton of like youth trainers
that start in like their lower 20s but
like teenagers aren't going to pay for
elite hoops and so like I remember when
I popped it on to to I think 25 plus it
had like an immediate effect of like
more uh you know just better performance
you know more can and this is where I
need my tracking better but you know
from for my purposes just looking at the
big picture and kind of knowing how
things perform like I've been able to
get a pretty good idea of where it
stands but like you know conversions are
better the metrics on Facebook's ad
dashboard were a little bit better and
it made sense to me it's like oh man
maybe I was like serving all these ads
to teenagers who who have no you know
they're interested in basketball but
they're not going to pay $45 for an app
um so you learn like little things like
that along way that's targeted towards
coaches 100% and I'm a big believer in
kind of bootstrapping the process
yourself because like when you're
spending the money that Apple puts into
your account like you feel it
differently you know it's not like
you're you're playing with your own
money so like if it doesn't work like
then it doesn't work you know so uh but
again that kind of goes back to think of
thinking of it as like less an indie app
and more of like something that I
actually want to grow so um but yeah all
of this rambling to say it it it's
definitely my most uh financially
successful app for sure um especially
this last week so that big feature
launched last Tuesday a week ago
tomorrow and I'm really interested to
see how conversions are starting
tomorrow because that's when I popped on
a hundred extra dollar a day because
before that before that feature launched
I was doing $60 a day and then I was
like well hey let's just see what
happens so uh did a new where did that
come from then the 100 like the idea
behind it or the number or or or what
part of it well well hold on let me re
ask that then uh what is the when you
said the $100 a day I thought you were
meaning that in Revenue you're saying oh
in your price okay so the revenue since
you know from about 7 eight days ago
it's anywhere from 300 to 600 that it
makes a day and I had been spending $60
a day in ads 30 on Apple search ads 30
in meta but when I launched that huge
new feature yeah ad spin so 60 on ad
spin a day when I launched that big huge
feature last Tuesday I did a new ad set
and added $100 a day just for that ad
set so that puts puts me up to 160 so
130 on meta and 30 on Apple search ads
um and you saw a jump in Revenue then
after that you know I the jumping
Revenue has been there since before I
started that $100 additionally on there
and I think
where came from basketball season's in
full swing so that's definitely the
biggest uh that's the biggest Factor so
like I'm thinking if I'm if I'm in
basketball season and things are working
then I'm going to try and double down
and see like if this additional $100
really like moves the needle tangibly
for me um and yeah and we can do an
update a year from now to see how it
went I guess next year um yeah yeah it's
interesting we we've talked about it
some before and certainly lots of people
on the show we've talked about it where
it's like there's some apps where you
can play the traditional marketing game
of you know around iOS releases and go
you know all the different people in the
tech press and uh but those are like
productivity apps or apps that are
general public apps that you can sort of
Leverage the fact that you're part of
the developer
Community Apple Enthusiast
Community yeah whereas you know an app
like Hoops is very much not that so like
you're probably unless you got like an
apple feature where they they push it to
such a wide audience that some
percentage of them will be interested
customers for the most part you know a 9
to-5 article is probably not going to
do uh a whole lot for you compared to
you know something in on Instagram like
an influencer in the basketball world or
whatever not even basketball world but
coaching world and funny mention that
because I'm trying influencer marketing
next year too that exact idea oh really
okay that's something I'm I'm really
interested in um not necessarily so much
for me because I don't I don't know how
much that's going to move the needle on
like white noise apps uh but certainly
with a lot of people I talk to for my
job uh there's a lot of apps where it it
sounds like that is the best way to get
to your customers to like find somebody
who's A influencer in that Arena who has
a big audience um and do some sort of
deal with them um whether that's like an
influencer campaign where they get a a
cut a sale like an affiliate kind of
program or just ads um but it's not
something I've spent a lot of time
personally messing with so I'm it'd be
interesting to see how that goes and
we'll we'll talk about it for sure
because the so I keep saying this big
new feature I think I said it earlier in
the show it's it's a practice planner
but it can also be used for like
individual workouts um and that's what I
use it for a lot so me and uh my oldest
son vett like we do little dribble
drills in the garage in the morning and
like we put like his workouts in for
each morning in there so like we use it
ourselves and I was like man this would
be great like that's a great story to
tell for some basketball trainer out
there you know like hey you know I got
it set up with the Le Hoops I start the
workout on my phone I can follow along
interactively so I think it could really
work but I think that's going to be my
biggest expense so I'm going to ease in
really slowly because I'm sure they
charge you know not a cheap amount for
those things um yeah but I love trying
those things and I don't know growing a
product is something that the process of
it is actually really fun for me and I
didn't expect that like I love
engineering I love design like making
the practice planner it turned out
really pretty in my opinion like I there
are sometimes when I do something I'm
like man I really like how this turned
out and there are some things most of
the time where I'm like this is good
enough like when Elite hoop shipped like
it was good enough but like the practice
planner I feel is more of like man that
feels like a a Porsche like this looks
really
good and probably because I used so much
ux from shortcuts and the photos app so
you know but uh I think it's going to
it's something that's easy to Market
like the story of why you need it and
how it can help you is really easy to
come up with yeah um but it's weird
because like I'm at that point where I'm
really pinching myself cuz like even
when I sent you that text like a week
ago like man it made like 600 whatever
um you know that's new for me like I
haven't had a product do that and then
each morning I when I keep waking up I'm
kind of like all right it's the fun over
you know like is this the day where I
wake up and there's like no that's why I
was interested in where like figuring
out where that's coming from cuz it's
got to be something like did your is
your ASO improved uh uh so that's a good
one to check because I changed it up
when I did the release last Tuesday
because there was nothing about practice
planning in there before because it was
like all about sharing your plays now
it's like you can share your plays you
can run your practices you can save your
drills yeah and that's a big one because
a lot of coaches they'll look on Tik Tok
they'll look on Instagram they all
follow their favorite trainers and
they're always posting drills that's
their main form of content and coaches
save them everywhere like on notes
clipboards favorites collections on in
and so I gave them like one spot to save
all of it um and I think one reason why
it's going
to you know cu the the trial's one week
so I was going to say like maybe since
it released last Tuesday that's why
things were better but those conversions
are coming from before I even shipped
that but I think it's a mix of
basketball starting and I think the
people that are there now like pinch me
I'm about to sound like such a product
manager but the practice planner is
really going to make it here we go we go
sticky it's going to make the product a
lot more sticky because when you've
built up all your practices and you've
saved all your drills like you're you're
less likely to churn out of it because
you've built up so much of your personal
workflow in that um and so yeah I'll
text you uh I guess if if trials started
if I released this last Tuesday then my
trials would start converting Wednesday
right I'm really stupid with how all
this works um like a one we trial yeah
assuming they all have Tri so I'll I'll
let you know Wednesday how it goes but
like I said it's it kind I said this in
the blog post I just put out too like it
for the first time in my Indie career it
feels like I could
actually grow it into something that I
by my own personal metrics have wanted
to grow it too um and I just kind of
attribute that to just being around long
enough and doing the wrong things to
meet that goal not the wrong things for
everybody like if you just want to have
like you said your passion project I've
been there then do it but like that's
not what been wanting to do lately like
I've wanted to make something that could
solve a problem and make money I think
that's a big part of it though right
it's not just you've done the Reps and
now you know it's like you started this
with a different goal than spin Stacks
or your other projects the goal was not
to make this is going to sound bad but
it wasn't to make something you're proud
of to make a bable product to show other
iOS developers look at the craft I've
put into this it was to deliver a
product that people find valuable enough
to pay forh and those are different like
you're not making an art piece you're
making a business uh a valuable product
for people who do not care about iOS or
Swift exactly or animations or any of
that stuff they're looking for something
to make their lives a little better it's
it's so true and I think where we do
have a big Advantage especially people
like you and me is we've spent so many
years trying to make that really nice
app that we can put just enough of that
into the business
oriented you know project and it shows
because a lot of the feedback that I get
through emails is like this just is
nicer than the other apps you know which
is great and so like you can kind of it
becomes a competitive advantage to where
like you learn I think the growth for me
is like I know enough design in ux to
make it nice and feel great now but like
that can't be the only thing I'm
thinking about and that used to be like
the only thing I thought about and then
you'll end up with a nice looking
product that maybe just doesn't solve
real problems um and so when you can
kind of mash them together it it gets
you into this nice flow um and yeah
because basketball software has been
like such a boring area like that there
it's really uninspiring you know so it's
like that little animation that takes
you two seconds to put in but like you
know because you've perfected it or
spent too much time or learn the hard
lessons before um now that you can carry
it through with your experience and
doing it in a way to where it's additive
but it's not like your week's Focus um
you know that's where it kind of starts
to mesh a little bit better yeah and I
like I don't want to say that as in
the flourishing craftsmanship doesn't
have value no obviously you said
everyone that does that is a waste of
time come on you can't change it
now you're so right though it's it's
true I think us both doing this Dev
Advocate thing not even Dev Advocate
thing but working for companies that
provide uh tools for developers that are
trying to make money we I at least I'm
sure you feel this too am way more
exposed to the sort of Indie hacker
Community which is different than the
iOS Developer Community even though
they're both building usually iOS apps
but I think it's over-provisioned in the
other direction where it's like only
value like distill something down purely
to just it's like value to the user
build that in the most minimal way
possible and then ship it and then
iterate on that maybe but there's almost
like a lack of time spent on quality and
a lot of those feel like they become
flash in the pan products High revenue
for and then you know once the care it
collapses that can happen for sure yeah
and so I think obviously it matters
there I think the other thing is um you
know craftsmanship
I think it conveys value uh even if it
isn't the value in itself I think this
is why you know in the in the 2000s late
2000s everybody's website had you know
high resolution stock photography and it
you go to a site that has that and it
looks nice like this is a professional
not a Fly by Night operation that's
going to steal my credit card history
and then all these stock photo tools
like and free ones like un unsplashed or
whatever those started coming out and
all of a sudden the cost to getting
something that has a bunch of uh
royalty-free you know high quality
photos in it was like almost zero and
now every Fly by Night operation can
have those and look just as professional
and then you saw this total switch into
like minimalism or uh do you remember
like the Flathead is that what it's
called or flat head whatever that the
weird shaped people rein a buffer with
and I
think yeah and like people in the design
Community rolled their eyes a lot at it
but I think the reason for that is it
conveyed value if you don't care about
tech and you open a site that has a
stock photo of a person at a wooden
coffee table talking with a pencil in
their hand you're kind of like is this
real or is this a scam whereas if you
went to one that's all white and it had
that generic but like uh clearly it was
made by an artist or something because
you couldn't just go to unsplashed and
get stuff that custom fit your website
it was like this little detail that
subtly uh conveyed that this is a
valuable thing um and then you have like
uh stripe whenever they did their
landing page with the the animated
gradients and it was like you know what
that conveyed it conveyed value did it
matter no but you went to it and you're
like this is not just some Fly by Night
operation thing it was also fun and
maybe help them attract Engineers or
something um so I do think when you open
up an app and the welcome screen has
some fluid animations and it's clearly
not
janky immediately that conveys like this
is a serious app this isn't just another
AI wrapper that somebody made in like
two hours uh with some crossplatform
tool not that crossplatform tools are
bad but like
it there was time spent on this and
that's what I should expect going
through with that app so I do think that
there's there's absolutely real value
and perceived value in all those
craftsmanship things there is I think
the best way to put it is like measured
craftsmanship is like a competitive
Advantage now and I say measured because
like you can't go in the direction that
I used to go with spin SEC and just make
it all about making a pretty app but
it's like if you can take a problem and
solve it and add your dash of care to it
like it really stands out um and
anything can change tomorrow but like if
you download any of the basketball
coaching apps on the app store right now
and put them next to Elite Hoops like
it's night and day I mean because it's
just like they're not you know they're
not really cared for at all um and I
think that's I'm reaping all those
lessons I learned over the years and
putting that into like a positive motion
now to where it's like I don't lose
sight of what's going to make it grow
and now that I know just enough how much
time and how much effort is just enough
to make it look really feel really good
and really nice but not overdo it and
lose sight of the goal um is that happy
middle ground that I had to really find
um and it was a struggle and there's a
there's a quote that you said last year
that really actually stuck with me I
still remember it we were talking about
how I have this membership card in the
settings and like if you're subscribed
it'll it's like this it looks like a
fake like ID card like renews that you
know you know your plan your ID that
kind of stuff it like Elite Hoops
Coaching Club you know and it just looks
like this nice ID card but like I had
this little async issue to where like it
would flash in few instances like if you
open the app up two settings I'd get the
response down I'd see that they're Pro
the Swift UI you know view would render
and be like oh they're on Pro so switch
out the view and like before you were
mentioning how like if that was spin
stack like it' just be a nogo I would
spin as much time as it took to solve
that problem before I shipped whereas
this time I'm just like you know what
that's that's I'm going to live with it
and I'll fix it later or I won't fix it
later but it's not going to move the
needle on like you know if someone
subscribes or not but it's like
something that all definitely notice and
so it's like it's about learning those
things as an indie developer you know
what is truly worth spending your time
on and again when when you're in our
cohort of Indie devs where you're
married and you have kids time is so
limited so it's like you have no choice
but to be laser focused to actually make
it worth your while because you're going
to be in a spot where you're tired or
exhausted at the end of the night but
you still kind of want to get something
done or you're in the morning and you're
full of that Creative Energy and like
maybe all you want to do is work on
making something look really cool and
splashy but it's like I got to be
realistic you know like I got one hour
before I clock into my job like what can
I do yeah um what's nice enough um and I
think that's the biggest lesson that I
would kind of give to people in a
similar spot um and when I hit that
conference circuit like the legend of
Charlie Chapman who who's at every
single one
I'll give a similar talk or something
like that but um yeah I mean it's just
like you don't learn it unless you go
through it and that's how it was for me
and some people have gotten that right
away and been successful a lot quicker
but uh I just like doing things the hard
way and taking several years to learn
simple
things yeah it's interesting like I'm
kind of going back and forth on this now
as I say it out loud but I do think
there's an
interesting
reality with especially with side
projects maybe this applies if you're
doing this full-time Indie as well where
time isn't isn't finite like it like it
is literally but like it feels like
especially as you know like you said as
parents who are doing this on the side
like I have only a sliver of time that I
can really spend on this stuff but the
reality is the time I spend on this
stuff is not you know add up the amount
of extra hours I have and put them
together it's really
like in these big waves of when I'm
really excited and passionate about what
I'm working on and when I'm not and
something I've definitely learned about
myself is I can't force it um the way
that I used to like you said sometimes
you're just tired or you've spent
yourself um but what I can do is
find find interesting things to like
jump start
my dtive energy if that makes sense so
like you know I I guess I haven't talked
about it here cuz I haven't been doing
the show frequently enough but I have
another app I have a Mac app actually
I've been working on called uh screen
frames that's the name currently now
anyway um I still haven't released it I
built it really fast with the idea that
I was going to try and release it fast
following Yi's like 222 method of like
delivering something really really fast
and I did the first two twos and then
the last part where you actually ship it
to the App Store it's not there but it
is I did ship it quickly to to people
for free um and it it just for context
it's like a screenshot for adding like
frames Apple device frames around your
screenshots uh but it's like a very very
Mac appy version of that anyway doing
that I was super excited about it and
got really into it but the reason that I
haven't shipped it is that is not
because
I didn't follow through it's because it
actually got my creative juices going
enough goodness to do things that I've
been trying to do in Dark noise for
forever but like this job for me doesn't
sound like it's done it to you as much
but every time I switch jobs it's it's
usually I have a bunch of Milestones
like usually I say um I feel completely
worthless for the first 6 months and I
have to be okay with feeling worthless
because I'll start feeling really bad
about myself 6 months is when I start to
feel like I'm adding value to the team
for the first time a year is when I feel
like I'm actually worth maybe what
they're paying me uh hopefully by that
point um but another one of those
Milestones is for the first year that
I'm working anywhere uh and I've
switched jobs enough times that I can
kind of measure this all my side hustles
really take a big hit whether that was
Motion Graphics back in the day side uh
project dark noise whatever um and with
this job it's actually taken a longer
hit because I also career switched I'm
doing something different than I ever
did before and I'm in the last three or
4 months feeling like I'm getting that
side hustle itch again really um and
part of what got that really going for
me was doing this totally different
project I stopped trying to force myself
to to do things and so I do think
thinking of time in that way is is
useful you you have more time than
you're actually going to spend on things
almost
definitionally uh and at least for me
the only way I can sit there and work on
side coding stuff while me and my wife
watch a TV show after we put the kids
down the only way that I ever spend that
time doing side hustle stuff is if I get
excited about again and sometimes the
side project work I need to do isn't fun
and I think switching to something else
even if it's not the most valuable is
sometimes the most valuable thing
because it like reignites me working on
it oh there's a whole topic there that
is so true about and I think this is why
we are natural fits for a developer
Advocate role like working with new
technology or a new thing is so
gratifying to me like it just it makes
me feel like I just graduated college
again and I've had I've been lucky
enough to have this happen several times
this year so like one was I actually
wanted to do like a a side Pro I think
Tyler calls it a side side project like
a side project for your side project and
like my idea that for Hoops was like I
wish I could make this online generator
that would give you a practice plan like
you would say what age you had for your
team you would say how much time you had
you'd pick some Focus areas and it would
spit out a practice plan and like I have
not done webdev it's never been my forte
like I I've always built my own websites
using jeal deployment with netfi so like
I am Hands-On like in terms of like
making your own website like yes I Pro I
coded all of them but like never like or
now you asked the uh what's it called to
Cod it for you well I was going to say
and I use cursor to build that so I
ended up building that out and I had so
much fun like that might that might have
been the most fun I've had like
programming in a long time CU like there
was this like segment of devel like
software engineering that was
intimidating to me like web development
like I don't know how to like call chat
gpt's API I mean I know there's a
there's a JavaScript client for it but
it's like how do I hide my API key you
know like how do I set up the
environment variables you know all those
things that like I kind of just knew I
could learn but didn't want to SP
again that limited time on and so like
that's where I feel like things like the
AI stuff as like a companion have really
like yeah like almost uncovered my love
for software engineering all over
because when I built that I felt so like
just gr it was gratifying and when I
deployed it and like anyone can go to
Elite hoops right now and do it Elite
Hoops app you click tools at the top and
I was like I can't believe I made that
like you know it like does the API call
it is it's like the first time you uh
build an app and you touch your software
exactly all the practices it generates
with a unique URL and stores them in
nety blobs and you can like share the
link and it'll retrieve them and you
know all this
stuff and uh there's a I've been
tweeting about this too there's a NCA
scoring app uh that I'm going to end up
shipping and that was another thing
where I'm like ah this is this just
feels so fun and like yeah you know
you've got to you got to balance the
what you have to do with like what you
want to do I feel like otherwise cuz if
you always do what you need to do like
it's you get in the do drums and that's
where things kind of sink and stop so
like you're more productive I think with
the Indie stuff when you let yourself
just kind of get that creative outlet
and just work on something that's just
fun um because you get it out of your
system a little bit you get that boost
and then the boring stuff that you kind
of have to do you get a little bit more
juice to power through it and that's
kind of why that find you get momentum
like you can carry that momentum into
the into the normal app yeah it because
like I immediately started on the
practice planner when I realized I
wanted to do it and it just seemed like
this boil the ocean problem so I
actually paused it and I made like the
free version of the one on the website
that I was just talking about and like
then I transitioned back into the
practice planner and that was a really
good exercise for me because one I
learned what an MVP of it looks like and
I learned that I could just give it away
for free and two like I did that
creative itch I did a whole new like web
technology all that stuff that I've
never used like the ser lless functions
all those things and then I slid into
the practice planner with like a new
kind of reinvigorated focus on it and
was able to do it and then with like the
NCAA app that I'm doing I deployed my
own API which I've never done and you
know I was joking around wow like I feel
like such a programmer now like you know
I I have my own API you're doing devops
yeah devops you know after being in the
industry for whatever 15 16 years I
finally feel like a programmer now but
like that was so fun like cuz I remember
like I was asking everybody like hey
like what should I use like you know how
much do you think this stuff costs and
you know do I use digital ocean AWS
which by the way everyone said don't use
AWS every single person so um you know I
chatted with a few more of my buddies to
like kind of figure out what to do and
ended up using this service called
render where you could use it like I use
nly my website so you point it to get a
re a repository and anytime you push to
main it deploys your your API and so oh
interesting yeah so like stuff like that
like you got to have fun doing this
stuff um and one point I was making I
don't know if I tied it back is like
that's why I think developer advocacy
has been so much fun and will be so much
fun is you kind of can make it your job
to do those things you know like uh if
I'm not feeling another iOS article this
week it's like man I'll just learn
something new about flutter that I don't
know and then I can turn that into an
article like even if it's something
basic like how do I do subscriptions in
flutter like that's still a valuable
piece of content in my role that I could
provide um and you got to switch it up
keep your brain working and and that's
the stuff that's always been fun about
software engineering oh yeah um so we're
like getting close on time but it it
wouldn't be an episode or Christmas
special with Jordan if we didn't talk
about the best-in-class book series uh
obviously you've been done with it you
were done with it uh last year yep but
have you made updates like what's what's
the latest on on the book series and
explain again what it is I can pull up
the hashtag numbers too yeah so the
best-in-class book series uh was a
fantastic way to drive myself to burnout
and Desperation by writing a book for
two and a half years is what it ended up
being um no it was so the the the
elevator pitch was I had an app called
spin stack years ago that I had sold to
a company to help you know pay we were
building a house during covid you know
cost shot up um so that's the whole
thing it's in it's in the back catalog
of our Christmas specials I'm sure if
you want the full story on that um but I
always wanted to write a book series and
so I split it up into five books because
one book would be much more sane and
reasonable um and I released updates
every two weeks on the books I think uh
it was apis design accessibility user
experience and just kind of like a I
don't know where this goes so it goes in
this book and so yeah it it took two and
a half years to write and my goal for
that going forward is now I'm in a
healthier place where I have been to
where I've been had to grind on it all
the time and what I want to do with it
going forward is one hash major update
when a new iOS version comes out and one
minor update throughout the year and so
over the past year I've done the one
minor update and I'm starting work on
the iOS uh iOS 18 update in January and
it's uh it's fun because like when I
leave it alone I'm happy to come back to
it and I found a really good natural
flow for it now that it's been out like
and done for over a year I found that
like a minor and a major is more than
enough like no one has ever not once
knock on one being like hey I wish you
would update this more like that's great
and it gives you a deadline which is
probably important to keeping up with it
exactly um but as far as sales it
doesn't sell hardly I mean if I had a
graph like chart that I could make real
quick like it would go down
year-over-year
um I think in
2024 it's May let me get my good old
Excel
spreadsheet yeah it's it's made $4,000
so that's like by far the lowest that
it's ever made um so like a few hundred
bucks but I mean it's still making
enough money to be worth updating it and
it's like kind of like one of my babies
you know it's like I can't believe that
I wrote like cuz like when I select all
of it in like the word processing tool
I'm like wow I wrote like 1,200 pages
over this stuff um and again go back to
the previous episodes it was more than
worth my time I mean I think lifetime
it's made like like
$60,000 so like it was more than I ever
could have dreamed of making but it's
one of the things now where it's like I
know where it fits into my life and I
come to it a few times a year and that's
I've put in enough work with it to where
that's it's it's in a position to be
able to do
that as as your friend I'm just so glad
that it's uh out of your life now oh
dude yeah especially towards the end it
was just uh it was really hard it was
definitely I mean there's a cliche about
the you know the pained artist trying to
finish a book or an author trying to
finish the book and it was like man this
is real like it's crazy that was just so
much work I'm glad that I did it I don't
see myself ever doing anything like that
again um but it is crazy to think back
like I am really proud of it now that
it's done like wow I wrote like on every
facet of iOS that I kind of know but the
the the hilarious part about all this is
like even coming to it a few times a
year if I would just spend like a day to
make the release process easier because
it takes forever it's really hard to
release oh that's right yeah I would
probably like update it every other
month with stuff like because I have
things all the time that I add in there
I'm like oh this is cool uh I didn't
know about this like in iOS 18.2 for
example there's a new initializer on
image to where you can give it a UT type
and like a file UR URL and it'll just
make the image for you from that and I'm
like that's fun that's interesting like
I just kind of happen to find that and
that's the stuff that I love putting in
the book but when it takes forever to
release it and like update the covers
and get it all uploaded it's just like
it's such a slog that like I have to
like wake up that morning and be like
all right like I'm going to get this out
now so one of these days maybe next when
we chat next year if I just make it easy
to release like it would have a ton of
updates throughout the year but uh since
that's not the reality though is it's
probably better from a marketing
perspective to have the twice a year
hits yeah for sure so yeah it's to the
point where like I wake up and like I'm
pleasantly surprised if it sold a copy
I'm like oh cool someone bought it you
know it happens like three or four times
a month probably I think is what it
averages out to um but before it was I
mean that was another fun memory like I
I will never forget like when I first
like tweeted like hey this is ready and
just seeing like the at the time I used
gumroad I was like oh my gosh like I had
never personally been through anything
like that of making all that money in
one day you know um I still I still
remember uh being in the Drive-Thru at
Starbucks in like somewhere along
i44 uh and finally getting to catch up
on my phone because it was that day and
you were texting us updates and I'm like
scrolling through our text chat and I'm
like oh my gosh like Jordan's doing
awesome yeah that was a really cool day
it it was and like I'm so sentimental I
I saved everything in day one like you
know every kid's first day like the
other day Remy my middle child has his
first basketball practice like he
decided you want to play basketball now
like I put everything in there and uh it
has this handy widget like you know in
your Journal X years ago and anytime I
see the day that like I shipped it and
released it I was I always read it I
always open it CU it's fun to go back in
that head space cuz you know when you
have it when you go with something like
spin stack that's made like I think at
its very best it made like 15,000 in a
year to making a lot more than that like
it kind of you're just like wow it is
possible to like do this somehow you
know some somewhere it just kind of all
works but uh yep that's that's where
it's at it's and I I imagine the
update's going to be the same every time
we do our famed Christmas special every
year is where it's like yep I do the
minor in the major every year um and for
this point it's kind of For the Love of
the Game um but luckily I love the game
so it'll it'll keep getting updated
there you go that's awesome all right
well uh I think we're reaching reaching
the end here um launch will continue to
live maybe going forward it will just be
this once a year uh but I think I think
I hope uh there will be much more
launched uh in 2025 than there was in
202 man it's a great show if you
actually listen to this uh and and also
feel that way let me know uh I will use
every want of your uh encouraging tweets
tootes SKS whatever it is that we're
doing now on the social networks uh as a
point of encouragement to tr to try and
fuel me to get get this thing back off
the ground again and if not you know
don't say anything I
guess so speaking of all of the social
networks we didn't even talk about I was
G to
say we'll save it for next year yeah uh
but speaking of all that where can
people find you and all of the many
things that you do on the internet you
know at this point I'm just like telling
them to go to my website so Swift
Objective C it's Swift and Objective C
cram together slout because there I list
all the 59 social networks that we have
to be a part of now so they're all there
whatever one we're going to join
tomorrow exactly yeah whatever new
hotness there is uh we we'll be there
but yeah my website's the best place to
just find anything I'm up to awesome and
uh if you want to keep up with the
latest goings on on launched it is also
on all of the different places launched
fm.com is the website where everything
lives uh we are on Blue Sky we're on
Twitter we're on Macedon we're on
threads uh I'm not on LinkedIn yet but
you know if you want me to be on
LinkedIn you going to share what you
learned about uh B2B sales from your
life experiences if you're not on Yeah
Yeah from the exactly exactly you know
what if enough people want me to be I'll
I'll join all right that's the end of
the show music's playing I'm going to
hit stop on the
recording and hopefully this thing
actually recorded